Guide to the Willard Gurdon Oxtoby Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Willard Gurdon Oxtoby papers
1950-1955
SC0719
Oxtoby, Willard Gurdon.
1.25 Linear feet
Collection consists of syllabi, exam schedules, reading lists, bibliographies, class handouts, and Oxtoby's notes and papers from classes he took at Stanford in history, humanities, philosophy, and political science, 1952-1955.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Associated Materials
Oxtoby's senior honors thesis can be found in the Stanford University Humanities Honors Program, Senior Honors Theses, Series Pre-1990, Box 15.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Willard G. Oxtoby, religious scholar and founding director of the Centre for Religious Studies at the University of Toronto, earned his A.B. in philosophy at Stanford University in 1955, where he was elected to Phi Beta Kappa.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists of syllabi, exam schedules, reading lists, bibliographies, class handouts, and Oxtoby's notes and papers from classes he took at Stanford in history, humanities, philosophy, and political science, 1952-1955.
Access Terms
Oxtoby, Willard Gurdon.; Humanities--Study and teaching (Higher).; Philosophy--Study and teaching (Higher).
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - History II CIV, Winter 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History 125 Near East, Fall 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Humanities 61 World Literature, Fall 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Humanities 100 Colloquium, Fall 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Humanities 62 World Literature, Winter 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Humanities 63 World Literature, Spring 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Humanities R113 Christian Doctrine, Fall 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Humanities 100 Colloquium, Winter 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Humanities 100 Colloquium, Spring 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Humanities 191 Senior Seminar, Fall 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Humanities 192 Senior Seminar, Winter 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Humanities 193 Senior Seminar, Spring 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Humanities R100 Comparative Religion, Spring 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Humanities 200 Senior Essay, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Philosophy 1 Logic, Fall 1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy 2 Ethics, Winter 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy 5 Intro. to Philosophy, Spring 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Philosophy 181 Philosophy of Language, Spring 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy 100 Greek Philosophy, Fall 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Philosophy 101 Medieval Philosophy, Winter 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy 160 Intermediate Logic, Winter 1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Philosophy 102 Modern Philosophy, Spring 1954 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Philosophy 172 Types of Moral Philosophy, Fall 1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Philosophy 104 Philosophical Background, Winter 1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Philosophy 170 Theory of Value, Winter 1955 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy 182 Metaphysics, Spring 1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy 184 Theory of Knowledge, Spring 1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Political Science, Introduction to Political Thought, Fall 1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Various graded examinations (Box 3)
    Restricted for 75 years from date of creation.